Hameet S. Boparai

Full Stack Developer

Portfolio Site
AWS Certification
02102471762

hameet.singh@hotmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/hameet-boparai https://github.com/Hameet

A Full Stack Developer who loves technology. I find the most satisfying problems to solve are the ones solved for people, with people. I love fixing things and solving simple to complex software problems. Problem solving is the reason I got into programming. I love writing code and the satisfaction I get from creating something.

I am also a Graduate in Science with several years of experience in the field of Food and Drug testing. My commercial experience complements my developer skills as I've always worked in teams and have acquired a wide array of soft skills.

Technical Skills

> Technologies and tools:

- o Javascript, HTML5, CSS3
- o Node.js, Express.js
- o React, Redux, APIs
- o Git, Test Driven Development
- o AWS Cloud Computing (EC2, VPC etc.)

> Recent Projects:

Embracing Blue - Code

This was my final project at EDA. A full stack app created to deal with mental health issues. It was built using frameworks such as React, Redux, Express, Auth etc. I had a great time working with my team and at the same time learned new technologies and agile development.

Mush-to-Muscles - Code

An on-going personal project of mine I am using as an online diary to make and store workout plans. This is a full stack app using technologies similar to the project above.

Wellington JavaScript for juniors - Code

This project is being sponsored in part by BNZ and overseen by highly experienced developers who are leading a group of Junior Devs including me to create a state-of-the-art JavaScript application for a local charity. Developers are involved in every stage of the project, from first discussions with the client to final delivery and deployment.

Transferable Skills

Communication: All of my previous roles have required excellent communication with colleagues. internal stakeholders and management. I have also presented to large audiences at work. I was given the task of presenting our final EDA project web app in front of a large crowd. I've written extensive project proposals and validation documents. I've excellent listening, empathy and feedback skills which I've used in both professional and academic environments.

Work ethic: Throughout my career, my high level of integrity and care for my work has led to employers developing a high level of trust and increased responsibilities

Great at dealing with conflict – Throughout my career as a Microbiologist I've dealt with a range of conflicts that arose and focused on allowing people to be heard, quickly defusing any difficult situations

Leadership – I have trained and supervised new staff numerous times and have filled in for a superior from time to time.

Project Management – Working as a Quality Control Technician for MSD I was in charge of several projects. I routinely worked with different internal stakeholders to change or improve existing testing/production processes or to create new methods and procedures from scratch. This also involved correspondence with international stakeholders in the US and the EU.

Employment History

Enspiral Dev Academy (Wellington)

Jan 2018 – May 2018

Full Stack Developer (Student/Apprentice)

At EDA I didn't only learn new technologies but subsequently used them to create websites. Apart from the technical craft mentioned above, I've acquired the following:

- > A vast array of human skills through working in a diverse environment and pair programming
- A better understanding of communication techniques for conflict resolution and team work
- > At EDA Presentation skills were also greatly emphasized and I've acquired a new-found confidence in my verbal communication
- > I've come to realize my passion for Front end development, UI, UX and the logic of back end

MSD - AH (Upper Hutt)

August 2014 – Mar 2018

Position Held: Quality Control Laboratory Technician

I have worked as a QC laboratory technician in the QC Sterility department for MSD-AH. A large part of my job was Technical Writing (reports, investigations & SOP's etc.). Some of my duties included:

- > Control testing on veterinary vaccines, intermediate components, solutions, raw materials, complaint samples and development samples to meet regulatory requirements
- ➤ Writing Method and Process validations to implement new or improve current testing procedures
- > Accurately record all test data and observations in accordance with Good Documentation **Processes**
- > Collaborated with Internal Stakeholders on projects to improve and validate new protocols for both testing and production
- > Performed Document control and accurately maintained databases and records

Asure Quality (Auckland)

May 2011- Aug 2014

Position Held: Laboratory Technician

I have worked in different divisions of the Microbiology department of Asure Quality.

- > Operated laboratory equipment such as PCR (DNA replication) among others
- Assisted in setting up various projects and setting up all the necessary paperwork
- Answered customer queries regarding results or delays in testing
- > Investigated situations wherein the inter-laboratory mistakes need to be tackled

Education

- ➤ **2018:** Full Stack Developer Boot Camp *Enspiral Dev Academy*
- > 2009-2010: Graduate Diploma in Laboratory Technology majoring in Microbiology, chemistry and Food Technology from Christchurch Polytechnic Institute of Technology
- ➤ 2005-2008: Bachelor of Science (Biotechnology) from Guru Nanak Dev University (India)

Personal Interests

Apart from coding daily some of my hobbies include traveling, gym, gaming, reading and Films.

References

Theresa Thomas (Quality Control Manager, MSD) **Praneta Joshi** (Senior Quality Control Technician, MSD) Mobile: 027-886-0425 Mobile: 021-126-3144